Balkar Singh Kalsi

#330, Darpan Enclave, Morinda, Ropar, Punjab / balkarskalsi@gmail.com / +91-82840-66617 / +91-95012-75842

Summary

A talented, enthusiastic and self driven UI/UX designer with more than 15+ years of experience in software industry in designing web and mobile apps. Also completed various webdesign projects which are in the areas of eCommerce, Brochure Websites, Logo Designing, Responsive Emailers, Landing Pages & Web Apps and Mobile Apps.

Skills

Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, FIGMA, Wireframing, Prototyping, Visual studio code, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, SCSS, Agile Methodology, JQuery, Manual of web and Mobile app Testing

Experience

Expense On Demand

Lead Design Consultant, New Delhi, Delhi

03/2018 - Present

- Design the UX & userflows for the SaaS product of ExpenseManagement Application
- · Participated in brainstorming sessions with User Story Owners and create workflows and design the product wireframes and share it with product team and after approval, convert them into HTML pages and share it with Developer team.
- Once the UI screens gets finalized verify the HTML templates on different browsers to to maintain consistent UI/UX experience.
- Maintain the sourcecode in version control systems using Git & SourceTree.
- Good Team player and a coordinator between teams and also involved in UI/UX testing.

Alpha Net Consulting

Lead Ul Designer, Mohali, Punjab

- 05/2016 01/2018
 - Designed the user workflows for the various projects, participated in brainstorming sessions with Product Owners, and implemented creative user-friendly UI screens using UI/Ux design standards.
 - Create product wireframes templated after the approval process and shared them as HTML templates with a Developer team.
 - Good Team player and a coordinator between teams and also involved in UI/UX testing.
 - Project Name: xBlinkx https://anetcorp.com/xblinx/

Senior UI Designer Grazitti Interactive, Panchkula

Senior Ul Designer, Panchkula, Haryana

06/2014 - 08/2015

- I was deployed at Adobe House on a Contract Basis for Onsite work- I worked on UI Designs for Adobe CCR.
- Apart from this, I worked with the Design Team for Marketo Templates & Responsive Emailers.

Applied Mobile Labs

Senior Software Engineer (Consultant), Noida, Uttar Pradesh 03/2013 - 05/2014

- I worked on English on Mobile application for both Web & Mobile.
- The objective was to teach English on Mobile to the needy.

Rimits

Web Designer, Chandigarh, Chandigarh

08/2012 - 03/2013

- Worked as Web Designer UI Designing & HTML Coding.
- · Involved in Image Editing
- · Also designed Mobile Apps UI

Indivar Software Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Sr. Web Designer, Mohali, Punjab

12/2010 - 08/2012

- Worked as Sr. Web Designer UI Designing & HTML Coding.
- Also worked in Image Editing, Logo / Brochure Designing / Template Designing.
- XHTML, Responsive Web Design, Logo Designing, Website Designing, Theme Designing.

Neoventis

Web Designer, Chandigarh, Chandigarh

07/2007 - 10/2010

- Worked as Web Designer UI Designing & HTML Coding.
- · Also worked in Image Editing, Logo / Brochure Designing

Certificates

Mobile App Design - From Sketches to Interactive Protypes, Learn HTML5 Programming from Scratch

Education

Master's in Computer Science & Application

Punjab Technical University, Chandigarh, Punjab 08/2010

Projects Completed

- ExpenseOnDemand Web Application
- Pricing Calculator
- anetcorp.com
- anetcorp.com xblinx
- · aurakitchens.in
- Indivar.com
- 3cubed.com.au
- waalechiropractic.com
- · alakazam.co.uk
- www.behance.net
- www.behance.net/gallery
- English-on-Mobile
- ExpenseonDemand.com